

Analyst seeking roles in Software Development, Application Support, Project Management. Experience in Splunk developer and admin, oracle weblogic Administration, Unix shell scripting and PL SQL developer. Forms and reports support, devops, oracle 19c.



Current Designation: Senior Software Engineer Analyst Total Experience: 7 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Wipro Technologies Pvt. Ltd Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Electronics/Telecommunication]

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Splunk, Weblogic, Weblogic Administration, Unix, Shell Scripting, SQL, PLSQL, Oracle Forms, Oracle Reports,

Jenkins, Bamboo, Tortoise SVN, Websphere Application Server, Confluence, JIRA, Financial Services, Banking,

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 18-Jan-21 Last Modified: 18-Jan-21

Summary

\u2022 Over all 7+ years of Professional experience in IT Industry

\u2022 ORACLE FORMS 6I & REPORTS 10g Migration to 12 C.

\u2022 Good knowledge on Upgrading Oracle Forms Reports and troubleshoot Oracle Forms and Reports.

\u2022 Resolve issues with Oracle Forms/Reports application.

\u2022 Testing of ORACLE FORMS & REPORTS on various development environments.

\u2022 Experience in implementing and configuring Web Services & SOA with WebLogic.

\u2022 WebLogic Administration, Monitoring and Troubleshooting using Admin Console and JMX.

\u2022 Cluster Configuration \u2013 Single Cluster, Multiple Clusters and Deployment over clusters.

\u2022 WebLogic's HttpProxyServlet and HttpClusterServlet configurations

\u2022 Installed oracle 12c Database and application server/infrastructure for Fusion middleware 12c

\u2022 Oracle RAC on Linux and Solaris installation, configuration and performance tuning.

Work Experience

Wipro Technologies Pvt. Ltd as Senior Software Engineer Analyst

Jul 2013 to Till Date

Splunk Development & Support - (Mar 2019 - present)

Project 1: ANZ Wealth

Duration: March 2019 - Till date.

Role: Lead Developer.

Team Size: 9

Roles and Responsibilities:

Development experience in customizing Splunk dashboards, Visualizations, Configurations, Reports and Search capabilities using customized Splunk queries, XML

Worked as a Splunk Admin for creating and managing apps, creating user's role, Indexers, scheduled reports generation and permissions to knowledge objects

Configuring and monitoring URL's, CPU usage, database, disk space for different applications

Monitoring various application's system performance and setup Alerts using Splunk

Creating Lookups, field aliases, calculated fields, Tags and Event types with Splunk

Extracting complex fields from different log files using Regular expressions(REGEX)

Experience on Splunk deployments and configuration management (Props.conf, Output.conf)

Providing extended support and fixing issues for Splunk monitored applications

Administered various Python scripts for monitoring and automation using Splunk

Preparing daily Team progress reports and providing updates to business leads

Project 2: ANZ Wealth Australia- Internal Application (EBBOS - Margin Lending).

Duration: January 2016 - Till date. Role: Lead Developer/Programmer

Team Size: 5

Environment: Solaris, Oracle 10G, Jenkins, UNIX, Python.

Other Tools Used: SOAP-UI, Control-M, Splunk, Putty, Beyond Compare, Eclipse, Toad.

Description: Margin lending is a form of gearing. In other words, borrowing money to invest.

Australians are very familiar with gearing when it comes to property investment and are

Recognizing that gearing can work for them when investing into the share market as well.

Margin lending is no longer just for sophisticated traders.

Experience in writing huge and complex scripts for business functions.

Involved in development effort estimations.

Worked on Project planning and helped team to understand the scope of work required for remediation.

Automating code releases with one touch shell script.

Tuned the ORACLE SQL queries and database, performed replication setup/backup/recovery, data export/import using

Data Pump, authentication, auditing, database monitoring, patch installation and other DBA tasks.

Experience in Banking and Financial business domain and its various intricacies involving data complexity, business

requirements, PCI compliance, Fraud Prevention and Risk handling algorithms.

Installing WebLogic server for oracle forms and reports.

Basic PYTHON scripting.

Control-M Job creation, execution, scheduling, calendar upload and alert configuration.

ORACLE FORMS & REPORTS support and part of Migration.

Usage of Oracle data pump for import and export of data across databases.

WebLogic server administration, domain creation, certificate configuration.

Has experience in Iterative and Incremental Agile, Scrum, Kanban project methodologies.

Worked on code redesign, development, Unit testing.

Supported testing team in understanding the business flow for legacy services by going through old Functional & Technical

Specs.

Support SIT, UAT and effectively participated in production deployment.

REDHAT Certified ENGINEER(completed couple of certificates)

Experience in creating SPLUNK, JIRA Dashboards.

Project 3: ANZ Wealth Australia- Internal Application (Gatekeeper)

Duration: January 2014 - October 2015

Role: Project Engineer, Application Support Lead

Team Size: 3

Environment: AIX 6.1, Windows 2008 R2, RHEL 5.6, RHEL 6.4

Other Tools Used: Toad, Control-M, Splunk, Putty, Beyond Compare, Eclipse, Sql developer.

Description: Gatekeeper is an administration system that was incepted to replace AFT Unit Trust system commenced in early 1996. Gate Keeper system went live in 1998 for Unit Trust and Master Trust products. Products such as pensions,

superannuation bonds etc. were added to the system later.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from PSG, Coimbatore in 2013

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
Splunk, SPL,Python,XML,SQL, Jenkins			
PLSQL, UNIX, Oracle, Shell scripting			
IBM MQ, WebSphere, REST API.			
Putty, Win SCP, FileZilla, SOAP UI,			
TOAD, SPLUNK, JIRA, SVN, Bit Bucket,			

Languages Known

	D 61 1		107.14	
Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak

1/22/2021	https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=2d01049be35fa4fd79563d1fb330119f5a595d5818120				
English					
Hindi					
Telugu					

Affirmative Action

Kannada

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No Job Type: Permanent / Temporary

Employment Status: Full Time, Part Time